Hey, we are talking about how to speeches, and I'm really excited because you've picked your topic now.
You know what it is, you want to teach us how to do.
Now don't forget, how to topic has to be culled down to a small manageable size and it has to be demonstrable, and what I mean by that is your how to speech must follow chronological order or steps.
You see in an informative speech you can just tell me the information, but in a how to speech you have to follow an order.
Let's say we're going to learn how to back a cake.
Is the first thing you're going to tell me to put the cake in the oven?
No!
What's the first thing you're going to tell me?
To go and get the ingredients, or go to the store and buy the cake mix, or whatever it is.
The first step.
So, as you're writing, remember you're going to follow a one, two, three, four, order.
Now, we're still going to have an introduction, we're still going to have a conclusion, but as far as three solid body parts, like what you would have in a persuasive or an informative speech, that's not what we're doing this time.
Now follow steps.
First you do this, second you do this, third you do that.
That's why our baby speech doesn't work out very well, because there's really no method to the madness.
You do what you do when you do it.
This, so I can learn it, needs to follow an order.
So now let's take a look at introductions and conclusions for the how to speech.